#### Juliano Boesel Mohr

+61 402 645 828 juliaaano@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/juliaaano

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with extensive knowledge in the Java platform and its surrounding technologies. Acquired vast experience with enterprise applications working mostly for the financial and pharmaceutical industries.

Interested in many aspects of enterprise systems, such as integration patterns, workflows, API's and event processing; as well as deploying these in cloud solutions with the support of, for example, tools like Docker, Kubernetes and Openshift. Also fond of BRMS platforms like Drools, from JBoss.

Enthusiasm for playing a role in projects that pursue high quality standards through the concepts of domain driven design, automated testing, continuous delivery, code reviews and so on.

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Software Engineer, Lendico Global Services GmbH

Oct 2015 - Sep 2016 (1 year) | Berlin, Germany

Lendico is a FinTech peer-to-peer lending company. It connects borrowers and investors without the need of traditional banking.

Being a key engineer of the core product, I have built from scratch a brand new accounting system with the best practices I had in hands: domain driven design, clean architecture, TDD, software defined infrastructure (e.g. Docker).

Fully responsible for the design and implementation of a mission critical integration solution of payment request generation. Adopted Apache Camel from end to end to successfully split, process, aggregate and deliver millions of messages asynchronously.

Involved in the important decisions that contributed towards the realisation of a distributed decoupled architecture, like for example, async vs sync communication, service idempotency, integration patterns and api design.

### Software Engineer, Clincase e-Clinical Technology Solutions

Dec 2013 - Sep 2015 (1 year 10 months) | Berlin, Germany

Software development of the Clincase solutions for clinical trials conducted by pharmaceutical companies. A complex system that offers end-to-end electronic data capture and clinical data management to conduct all types of clinical trials.

Responsible for designing new modules in an OSGi environment modeled to support the company's strategy and customer requests.

Maintenance of hundreds of application server instances in a cloud-like infrastructure. Introduced Docker by building container images of the entire software ecosystem.

Built integration solutions using tools like Apache Camel and Karaf with the purpose of automating tasks and connecting Clincase with external systems.

Built a REST API around some of the core services of the application.

### Software Engineer, Weev Solutions Ltda

Jul 2010 - Dec 2013 (3 years 6 months) | Florianopolis, Brazil

Project manager and senior developer of a Java Enterprise portal for sports centers management business.

Worked 2+ years in an off-shore project for a Dutch customer, building financial systems for the retail banking business.

Developer and consultant at the start-up of a large project for the Brazilian government, where an innovative solution with JBoss Drools was provided.

#### Software Engineer, TSM The Service Manager

Nov 2008 - Jun 2010 (1 year 8 months) | Sydney, Australia

Responsible for the re-write of the TSM product, a service management software solution that helps field service staff efficiently manage all aspects of their business activities.

Technical leadership as well as mentoring the development group to complete their tasks achieving maximum quality in their work.

Involvement in all stages of the project, such as database design, architecture definition, technologies used, implementation, etc.

Implementation utilizing Servoy, a development environment for building Java applications.

Development of other projects in Java EE and Struts with integration to legacy systems.

#### **Information Analyst, EDS Electronic Data Systems**

Mar 2006 - Jul 2008 (2 years 5 months) | Florianopolis, Brazil

Worked in a variety of large off-shore projects for top customers, such as American Airlines, Embratel and Bank of Amazon.

Responsible for software development, software testing, projects specifications, design and UML modeling.

Acquired valuable experience in the following industry areas: financial, transportation and telecommunications.

#### Java Developer, Dataprev Information Technology Co.

Sep 2005 - Dec 2006 (4 months) | Florianopolis, Brazil

System development and architecture design using main J2EE design patterns.

System analysis for the social welfare government industry, with emphasis on financial and budgetary area.

# EDUCATION & TRAINING

04/2012 to 12/2013, Graduate in Project Management

SENAC. Florianopolis SC - Brazil.

06/2003 to 12/2007, Bachelor in Information Systems

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina. Florianopolis SC - Brazil.

09/2000 to 07/2001, Exchange Student Program (Junior Year High School)

North College Hill High School. Cincinnati OH - United States.

#### **CERTIFIED**

SCBCD - Sun Certified Business Component Developer for Java EE 5

**SCWCD -** Sun Certified Web Component Developer for J2EE 1.4

**SCJP -** Sun Certified Java Programmer for Java 1.5

SCJA - Sun Certified Java Associate for Java SE